TIMOTHY DUNCAN

Python Developer

@ lily.williams@gmail.com @ github.io/lily.williams San Francisco, CA **229-828-1284**



SUMMARY

Python developer with 8 years of experience in finance and fintech. Wellacquainted with database engineering, data warehouses, and data processing. Knowledgeable in Python frameworks related to data such as SciPy, NumPy, Matplotlib. Cloudera certified Data analyst, PCPP-1 certification and Spark/Hadoop developer certification.

EDUCATION

B.S. Software Engineering

University of California, San Fransisco

GPA 3.8 / 4.0

EXPERIENCE

Python Developer

Revolut

= 2015 - 2018 San Francisco, CA

Revolut is a financial technology company that offers banking services. We offer accounts featuring currency exchange, debit cards, virtual cards, and vaults.

- Collaborated with Web Application Engineers, used Python scripts to load the data into AWS Cloud Cassandra database
- Visualised over 40 datasets with Matplotlib
- Involved in processing the streaming data as well as batch data using Apache
- Delivering projects with 1-2 days turn around time or even within hours

Python Developer

Bank of America

2012 - 2015 San Francisco, CA

Lauzon is a finance firm based out of San Fransisco, CA. They cater to over 30 local businesses and startups by providing custom finance software.

- Developed internal tools for text mining (sentimental analysis), and web crawler for collecting data by Python and SQL
- Used AWS Elastic Beanstalk service for deploying and scaling web applications and services developed with Java, Python
- Developed shell scripting and Python programs to automate the data flow on day-to-day tasks
- Analyzed the SQL scripts and designed the solution to Developed a custom ETL pipeline by using Python

Junior Python Developer

2018 - Present

San Francisco, CA

Lauzon is a finance firm based out of San Fransisco, CA. They cater to many local businesses and startups by providing custom finance software.

- Made over 800 insertions and 150 deletions to 4 central Firmware repositories in less than 3 months
- Participated in more than 4 projects per year from initial research and conceptual design through testing and implementation phases
- Developed data quality portal using Python scripting, increasing data quality by
- Communicated and coordinated with the project manager and coworkers to resolve 30+ build breaks a month

SKILLS

Programming

Python SciPy NumPy Matplotlib Django Flask SQL Java

Databases & Servers

AWS Django ORM MySQL ETL Cassandra MongoDB Hadoop Spark

Development

GIT SVN PyCharm

STRENGTHS

Time management

Prioritizes essential tasks so they are not rushed. Sets deadlines that ensure reaching milestones on time.

Adaptability

I remember that change is not personal and is inevitable. I break my projects into multiple parts so that if something goes wrong, I can quickly fix it.

Accountability

I take ownership of my mistakes. By doing that I learn what I did wrong so that it does not happen again.

CV Enhancy